Daria Minina

Nationality: Dutch, Belarussian Homepage: https://sites.google.com/view/daria-minina

Summary

I am a PhD Researcher at the University of Amsterdam under the supervision of Stefanie J. Huber and Cars Hommes. I received my MPhil in Economics with honors at Tinbergen Institute in 2020 and MSc in Economics with honors at the University of Amsterdam in 2018.

My primary research interests are Behavioral Economics, Experimental Economics, and Macroeconomics. I use laboratory experiments and survey data to study expectation formation of economic agents.

Positions and Affiliations

2020- PhD Researcher, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam School of Economics, Center for

Nonlinear Dynamics in Economics and Finance (CeNDEF), Roetersstraat 11, 1018 WB

Amsterdam

Research Interests

Primary: Macroeconomics, Experimental Economics.

Secondary: Household finance, Behavioral Economics, Game Theory.

Work in Progress

Learning in a Complex World. Insights from an OLG lab experiment

(status: R&R JEBO; slides available upon request)

jointly with Cars Hommes, Isabelle Salle and Stefanie J. Huber

The pass-through from inflation perceptions to inflation expectations

(status: submitted; slides upon request)

jointly with Stefanie J. Huber and Tobias Schmidt

The effect of macro and micro shocks on firms' price-setting decisions. The expectations channel (status: got access to the data set; obtained first empirical results)

Correcting biases is inflation expectations with information provision. Survey evidence

(status: got access to the data set; obtained first empirical results) jointly with Gabriele Galati, Richhild Moessner and Maarten van Rooij

Education in Economics

2020 - University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam

PhD in Economics

Advisors: Stefanie Huber, Cars Hommes

2018 – 2020 Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam

MPhil. in Economics (with honors)

Thesis Title: "Equilibrium Selection through Laboratory Experiments in a complex

OLG economy"

Advisors: Stefanie Huber, Cars Hommes

2018 University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam

Master of Sciences (MSc) in Economics (with honors) Specialization in Behavioral Economics and Game Theory

1/4

^{*-}presented by co-author

2015 **Belarussian State University, Minsk**

Master of Sciences (MSc) in Economics (with honors) Specialization in Mathematical methods in Economics

2009-2014 Belarussian State University, Minsk

Bachelor degree in Economics (with honors)

Internships

September 2022- Deutsche Bundesbank, Frankfurt am Mein

November 2022 Advisor: Tobias Schmidt

Other Training and Courses

June 14 – 2021 Online

Experimental Finance Virtual Summer School, University of Bonn

April 19 – 23 2021 **Online**

PhD course on Subjective Beliefs in Macroeconomics and

Household Finance

June 20- July 1 2016 Institute for capacity development, IMF, Washington DC

Certificate of completion (Course "Using DSGE-models for policy analysis")

December 4-18 2015 Joint Vienna Institute, IMF, Vienna

Certificate of completion (Course "Monetary Policy Analysis")

March 2-13 2015 **Joint Vienna Institute, IMF, Vienna**

Certificate of completion (Course "Macroeconomic Forecasting")

2013-2014 **BEROC, Minsk**

Certificate of completion (Postgraduate School in Economics)

Online courses

October 2016 International Monetary Fund

Verified certificate of completion ("Financial Programming and Policies II")

December 2015 Verified certificate of completion ("Macroeconomic forecasting")

November 2014 Verified certificate of completion ("Debt Sustainability Analysis")

July 2014 Verified certificate of completion ("Financial Programming and Policies")

Academic References

Professor Cars Hommes University of Amsterdam Roetersstraat 11, 1001 NJ Amsterdam, Netherlands

+ 31205254246

C.H.Hommes@uva.nl

Assistant Professor Stefanie Huber

University of Amsterdam

Roetersstraat 11, 1001 NJ Amsterdam.

Netherlands

ivetherianus

s.j.huber@uva.nl

Professor Joep Sonnemans University of Amsterdam

Roetersstraat 11, 1001 NJ Amsterdam,

Netherlands +31205254249

J.H.Sonnemans@uva.nl

Professional and Teaching References

Mikhail Pranovich International Monetary Fund 700 19th Street, Washington DC, USA Dr Tobias Schmidt Deutsche Bundesbnak Mainzer Landstrasse 46, 60325 Frankfurt am Main, Germany Kristina Manysheva Northwestern Univeristy Evanston, Illinois, United States

^{*-}presented by co-author

Teaching Experience in Economics

2023 -	University of Amsterdam Teaching assistant for <i>Mathematics 1: Calculus</i> (Undergraduate Course, Instructor: Jop Schouten)
2020 -	Teaching assistant for <i>Multivariable Calculus</i> (Undergraduate Course, Instructor: Maurice Koster)
	Teaching assistant for <i>Mathematical Economics II</i> (Undergraduate Course, Instructor: Jan Tuinstra)
2020-2022	Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam Teaching assistant for <i>Behavioral Macro and Complexity Summer School</i> (Graduate level, Instructor: Cars Hommes)
2020	Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam Teaching assistant for <i>Econometrics II</i> (MPhil Course, Instructors: Bas van der Klaauw, Hans Bloemen)
2016-2017	Belarusian State University, Minsk Teaching assistant for Corporate Finance (Undergraduate Course)

Awards, Scholarships, and Certificates

Scholarships Full scholarship, Tinbergen Institute scholarship program for Research Master

students

Amsterdam Merit Scholarship, University of Amsterdam

Conferences and Seminar Presentations

2023	The 3rd MORSE conference (Maastricht, the Netherlands)
2023	CeNDEF@25 workshop (Amsterdam, the Netherlands)
2023	EEA-ESEM 2023 (Barcelona, Spain)
2023	5th Behavioral Macroeconomics Workshop (Bamberg, Germany)
2023	Experimental Finance 2023 (Sofia, Bulgaria)
2023	IMEBESS 2023 (Lisbon, Portugal)
2022	The 11th Nederlandse Economendag (NED) (the Hague, the Netherlands)
2022	Research Seminar at De Nederlandsche Bank (Amsterdam, the Netherlands)
2022	WE_ARE_IN Macroeconomics and Finance* (Basel, Switzerland)
2022	4 th Behavioral Macroeconomics Workshop (hybrid: online and in Bamberg, Germany)
2022	12th annual meeting of the Society for Experimental Finance (Bonn, Germany)
2022	12th Workshop on Theoretical and Experimental Macroeconomics (Berlin,

^{*-}presented by co-author

	Germany)
2022	49th OeNB Economic Conference and 35th SUERF Colloquium (Vienna, Austria)
2021	Brown Bag Seminar of the Research Centre of Deutsche Bundesbank* (Frankfurt, Germany)
2021	27th International Conference on Computing in Economics and Finance (online)
2019	2018 Conference of Young Researchers in Economics and Finance (Minsk, Belarus)

Professional and Academic Experience

10/2017 – 06/2018	Centre for Blended Learning, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam Student Assistant (designed educational modules for the online platform)
11/2016 – 08/2017	Embassy of the United Kingdom in Belarus, Minsk Economic Diplomacy Assistant
06/2015 – 10/2016	Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk Senior economist (full-time)
07/2014 – 16/2015	Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk Leading economist (full-time)
09/2013 – 07/2014	Research Institute of the Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk Junior Research Fellow (Internship)
07/2007 – 04/2014	BPS-Sberbank, Minsk Economist

Computer Skills

Matlab, R, Stata, Python, Eviews, Otree, Z-tree

Languages

Languages Russian (native), English (fluent), German (intermediate), Dutch (intermediate)

^{*-}presented by co-author